{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "A disease that can be spread from one person or species to another.",
			"back": "communicable disease"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "Occurs when new cases of a disease in a human population substantially exceed the number expected based on recent experience.",
			"back": "epidemic"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "A common virus that is asymptomatic in 80% of people carrying it, but characterized by small blisters on the lips or genitals in symptomatic infections.",
			"back": "herpes simplex"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "Awareness that unseen life-threatening injuries may exist when determining the mechanism of injury.",
			"back": "index of suspicion"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "A medical condition caused by the growth and spread of small, harmful organisms within the body.",
			"back": "infectious disease"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "A virus that has crossed the animal/human barrier and infected humans and that kills thousands of people every year.",
			"back": "influenza"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "Emergencies that are not caused by an outside force; illnesses or conditions.",
			"back": "medical emergencies"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "An inflammation of the meningeal coverings of the brain and spinal cord; it is usually caused by a virus or a bacterium.",
			"back": "meningitis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "An inflammation of the meningeal coverings of the brain and spinal cord; can be highly contagious.",
			"back": "meningococcal meningitis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "A bacterium that can cause infections in different parts of the body and is often resistant to commonly used antibiotics; it is transmitted by different routes, including the respiratory route, and can be found on the skin, in surgical wounds, and in the bloodstream, lungs, and urinary tract.",
			"back": "methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "The general type of illness a patient is experiencing.",
			"back": "nature of illness"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "An outbreak that occurs on a global scale.",
			"back": "pandemic"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "Emergencies that are the result of physical forces applied to the body; injuries.",
			"back": "trauma emergencies"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "A chronic bacterial disease, caused byMycobacterium tuberculosis, that usually affects the lungs but can also affect other organs such as the brain and kidneys; it is spread by cough and can lie dormant in a personâ€™s lungs for decades and then reactivate.",
			"back": "tuberculosis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-15-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "The strength or ability of a pathogen to produce disease.",
			"back": "virulence"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-15",
		"label": "Chapter 15"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}